我叫巴里·艾伦  是现今世上速度最快的人
My name is Barry Allen, and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present.
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
And now our world is more dangerous than ever.
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
And I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
-我爸爸是不是真的  -凯特琳  你父亲死了
- Is my dad even really-- - Caitlin, your father is dead.
-爸爸  -你找到我了
- Dad? - You found me.
小凯  我想补偿你
I want to make it up to you, Caity.
我确实应该陪伴在你身边
I really should've been there for you.
如果我爸一点都不剩的话
Icicle wouldn't have gone to all this trouble
冰柱不会这么大费周章地去杀他
to kill my dad if there wasn't a piece of him still left.
我们找到了德怀尔  给他了解药
We got Dwyer, we gave him the cure,
但是另一个蝉却出现了
but another Cicada showed up.
她想告诉你们她的秘密
She wants to tell you her secret.
是有人指示你去做的
Someone instructed you to do it.
艾尔伯德·斯旺
Eobard Thawne.
爸爸  拜托别这么做
Dad, please don't do this!
诺拉  如果你再试图回到过去
Nora, if you try to run back in time again,
我会在神速力里感受到
I will feel it in the Speed Force.
再见  诺拉
Good-bye, Nora.
你把我们的女儿送回到了未来
You took our daughter back to the future?
我没有别的选择
I didn't have any other choice.
我  是我们  巴里
I? It's we, Barry.
我们  她是我们的女儿
We. She's our daughter,
-不只是你的  -我知道
- not just yours. - I know that.
但你还是把她留在了那里
But you left her there anyway?
我无法相信她  爱瑞丝
I can't trust her, Iris!
那让我们都陷入了危险
That puts all of us in danger!
那是你的感受  巴里
That's how you feel, Barry.
为什么不问问我的感受
What about asking how I feel?
我不认为有必要问
I didn't think I had to!
当然没有必要
Of course you didn't.
你当然没有必要问  巴里
Of course you didn't, Barry!
你总是认为只有一种解决办法
You always see one way through a problem
而且不顾我的想法
and damn what I think.
等等  你这是什么意思
Wait, wait, what the hell does that mean?
我们一起经历了这么多
You know, we have been through so much crap,
去看过了这么多心理治疗
we have been through so much therapy
然而你还是
and you are still--
还是会感情用事
still making decisions based on your emotions!
因为这次我是对的
'Cause I'm right this time!
闪点
Flashpoint?
抛下我去神速力
Going to the Speed Force and leaving me?
那几次你也是对的吗
Were you right those times too?
你以为我想要这样做吗
You think I wanted to do this?
这对我来说很容易吗
That this was easy?
看到诺拉看着我  求我原谅她
Seeing Nora looking at me, asking for forgiveness
知道这可能是我最后一次见到她
knowing it might be the last time I ever see her?
我最后一次见到她是什么时候  巴里
What about the last time that I get to see her, Barry?
我甚至都没有告别的机会
I didn't even get a chance to say good-bye!
该死  爱瑞丝  她几个月来一直在骗我们
Damn it, Iris, she lied to us for months!
她解释了原因
And she explained why!
她一直在和斯旺合作吗
That she was working with Thawne?
你不介意这一点
That doesn't bother you.
对  我不介意
No, it doesn't.
也许如果他在你面前杀死你妈妈的话
Maybe if he killed your mother in front of you,
你就会有不同的感受了
you'd feel differently.
也许感受不同 巴里
Maybe you feeling differently, Barry,
就是我们需要共同做决定的原因
is why we should have made this decision together.
她只是想要见你  巴里
She just wanted to meet you, Barry.
她素未谋面的父亲
The father that she never knew
只有一个人能教她如何做到这一点
and there was one person who could teach her how to do that.
你真的很难理解
Is it really so hard to understand
她为什么去找他吗
why she would go to him?
我是否理解并不重要
Doesn't matter if I understand it.
斯旺在操纵她
Thawne is manipulating her.
他被关在死囚牢房  巴里  他要怎样操纵她
He's on death row, Barry. How is he manipulating her?
如果这是其他人  你会支持我的
You know, if this were anybody else, you'd back me.
但因为这是诺拉  是我们的女儿
But because it's Nora, because it's our daughter,
那个终于不再恨你的人
the person who finally stopped hating you,
你拒绝认清这有多危险
you refuse to see how dangerous this is.
你提到感情用事
I mean, you talk about making decisions based on emotion.
照照镜子吧
Look in the mirror.
没有我爸爸的这些年
All those years without my father
你给了我第二次机会
and you gave me a second chance.
现在我又一次失去了他
And now I've lost him all over again.
我让你失望了  小极速者
I failed you, Little Runner.
不  这是我的错
No, this is my fault.
我不应该在与你合作这件事上欺骗他们
I should've never lied to them about working with you.
也许不应该
Well, perhaps not.
我把一切都搞砸了
I screwed everything up.
现在我甚至都不能帮他们抓住蝉
And now I can't even help them catch Cicada
因为如果我进入神速力的话  我爸爸会知道
because my dad will know if I run into the Speed Force.
他一定会知道
He most certainly will.
等等
Wait.
你进入神速力好多次
You've run into the Speed Force hundreds of times.
然而我爸爸和其他极速者
And my father, other speedsters,
从来没有感受到过你
they never felt you coming.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
斯旺  告诉我你是怎么做到的
Thawne, tell me how you did it.
-诺拉  -告诉我  斯旺
- Nora. - Tell me. Thawne!
这个方法不适合你
It's not for you.
我需要见我爸爸
I need to see my father.
拜托了  如果有方法
Please, if there is a way
能让我在不被他察觉的情况下回去
I can go back in time to see him undetected,
你得告诉我怎么做
you have to tell me how.
我曾经很崇拜你父亲
I used to idolize your father.
我想成为像他那样的人
I wanted to be just like him.
但那不是我的命运  我注定要成为他的反面
But that was not my fate. I was to be the reverse.
在各种方面
Opposite of him...
成为他的对立面
in every way.
所以我没有进入神速力
So instead of tapping into the Speed Force
去获取我的能力
to access my powers...
而是创造了我自己的
I created my own.
你创造了自己的神速力
You created your own Speed Force?
是的
Yes, I did.
我可以利用它回到过去吗
And I can access it to go back in time?
不仅如此
That and more.
你能教我怎样使用它吗
Can you teach me how to use it?
我必须警告你  诺拉
Well, I-- I have to warn you, Nora.
有一点点负能量
It's a little bit negative.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十九集
塞西尔和西斯科呢
Hey, where is Cecile and Cisco?
塞西尔在接替保姆照顾孩子
Cecile's relieving the nanny.
西斯科去找穿越者
And Cisco went to talk to Breacher
谈谈如何追查二代蝉
about how to track Cicada II.
好吧
Okay.
爱瑞丝呢
Where's Iris?
我真的不知道
Uh, I honestly don't know.
我们现在的看法并不完全一致
We're not really seeing eye to eye right now.
因为
Because?
因为我把诺拉永远地送回家了
Because I took Nora home for good.
-诺拉走了吗  -就这样吗
- Nora's gone? - Just like that?
唯一能做的就是
Well, only thing to do, really,
因为我们不能相信诺拉
because Nora can't be trusted.
我可以从你的表情看得出你很难过
I can deduce from your faces that you're upset,
但是你知道需要揭露真相
but you understand the truth need to be exposed.
是的  这我们明白
Yes, we understand that.
你不明白这是一个家
What you don't understand is that this is a family.
你没把任何人当家人看待
You didn't include anyone in this.
小长颈鹿
Oh, look. Baby Giraffe--
歇洛克  你做得够多的了
Sherloque, you've done enough.
-好吗  -我没做够
- All right? - Oh, I have not done enough.
我们还要抓另一个蝉
We still have another Cicada to catch.
他说你做够了
Man, he says you've done enough.
也许是吧
Well, perhaps I have.
我得接这个电话  喂
I got to take this. Yeah?
既然西斯科不带我一起去
Look since Cisco didn't take me with him,
我要整理一下二代蝉的文件
I'm gonna round up the Cicada II files.
我和塞西尔明天会仔细看一下
Cecile and I are going to go over them tomorrow,
看看有什么异样的地方
see if anything makes my nose wiggle.
你没事吧
Are you gonna be okay?
我真的不知道
I honestly don't know.
各位  是中城警局打来  我们有大麻烦了
Guys, this is CCPD. We've got a big problem.
护士半夜听到一声巨响
The nurses heard a crash in the middle of the night
但是没人看到任何事
but nobody saw anything.
等他们赶到那里的时候
By the time they got here,
格蕾丝已经不见了
Grace was gone.
从这个玻璃的热变形来判断
Judging by the thermal warping in this glass,
一股巨大的高温热量爆炸把窗户炸开了
an energy blast with a lot of heat took out the window.
但我真觉得我们不需要任何线索
But I don't really think we need any clues
也知道是谁带走了她
to know who took her.
未来的格蕾丝带走了过去的格蕾丝
Future Grace steals past Grace.
我都不知道自己绑架自己
I don't even know if there's a police code
警察该采取什么样的措施
for kidnapping yourself.
上面写些什么
Hey, what's it say?
格蕾丝的昏迷状态很稳定
Grace's coma is stable.
只要未来格蕾丝照顾小格蕾丝
As long as future Grace is looking after younger Grace,
她就不会有生命危险
her life's not in any danger.
我们还是没有办法找到她们任何一人
We still have no way to find either of them.
事情会变得更糟糕吗
Could things get any worse?
唐怀瑟站点
加班吗  唐豪瑟医生
Working late, Dr. Tannhauser?
或是提早上班  取决于你如何看待
Or working early, depending how you see it.
我是来和你说晚安的
Well, I stopped by to say good night.
看来我该说早上好
So I guess I'll say good morning.
早上好  JP
Good morning, J.P.
别过来  站住
Get back! Hold it right there!
托马斯
Thomas?
我想冰柱不会留下任何冰冻的指纹吧
I don't suppose Icicle left any frozen fingerprints behind?
是的  但扩充口
No, but this docking station
内嵌着碳填充的外壳材料
is lined with a carbon-filled Kapton polymide.
是宇航局用来建造探测器
NASA uses it to build probes
为了能到达太空最冷的地方
meant for the coldest reaches of space.
这里有很多刚刚留下的水洼
There's a lot of fresh puddles in here.
你觉得是他偷走的东西维持这里的冷度吗
You think he stole whatever kept this place cold?
-假设不只是冷  -他要这个东西做什么
- Try way beyond cold. - Why would he want it?
这你得等卡拉填完盗窃报告
You're going to have to ask Carla
去问问她了
when she's done filing the theft report
或是等凯特琳来了问问她
or Caitlyn when she gets here.
最近我很困惑
I'm not sure about much lately.
巴仔
Hey, Barr.
爱瑞丝走之后你有和她聊过吗
Have you talked to Iris since she left?
我只是给她一点空间
I'm just giving her some space.
只是确保你不要给得太多
All right, just make sure you don't give her too much.
正确的选择吗  你在说什么
The right choice? What the hell are you talking about?
你骗了我20年  和我说我父亲死了
You lied to me for 20 years and told me my father was dead.
这算是什么正确的选择
How the hell is that the right choice?
你父亲困在一个冰怪体内  凯特琳
Your father is trapped inside an ice monster, Caitlyn.
我能怎么做
What was I supposed to do?
周末的时候和他分摊抚养权吗
Split custody with him on the weekends?
我不知道  你可以试着把真相告诉我
I don't know. You could try telling me the truth.
但又何必告诉你女儿呢
But why tell your daughter anything?
好笑的是  我不记得你告诉我
Funny, I don't recall you telling me
你把那个怪物放出来了
that you let the monster out of the prison.
因为你从来没和我说过他被关着
Because you never told me he was in a prison!
而这么多年来  我本可以为爸爸研制解药
And now all these years that I could've been working on
现在没有了
a cure for dad are gone!
我们也许永远也救不回他了
We may never get him back.
至少你有人可以责怪
Well, at least you have someone to blame.
这个责任永远在妈妈身上
Moms are always here for that.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
找到冰柱我就会没事
I will be as soon as we find Icicle.
我妈和我说他偷走的东西
My mom told me what he stole.
是一个制冷雾化器原型
It's a prototype Cryo-Atomizer.
-他能用那个来做什么  -不会有好事
- And what can he do with that? - Nothing good.
我在州北的联络人毫无发现
My contacts upstate got nothing.
我甚至找了国防部的克里舒高斯  无功而返
I even tried Kritschgau at the DOD. Nada.
没人能分派一些人手来帮我找二代蝉
Nobody can spare the manpower to help find Cicada 2.0.
那《公民报》呢
Hey, what about The Citizen?
有什么蝉的新线索吗  爱瑞丝
Any fresh leads on Cicada? Iris?
地球呼叫爱瑞丝
Hello? Um, Earth to Iris?
拉尔夫  等等
Ralph, wait!
巴里  我不知道我是否能原谅你这么做
"Barry, I don't know if I can ever forgive you for this."
我想你这里漏了一个逗号
I think you missed a comma there.
你能不能别管闲事
Can you stay out of it for once?
她不是在说笑  真的很生气
She's not kidding. Super mad.
不  爱瑞丝
No. Look, um, Iris,
我知道巴里的性格
I know how Barry can be.
但是你们就像是超级英雄皇室版的梅根和哈里
But you guys are like the Meghan and Harry of superhero royalty.
你们的爱是永恒的
Your love is eternal.
-你们会好好谈谈  -我们谈过了
- You two will talk and-- and-- - We did talk.
我要诺拉留在这里  他不愿意
I want Nora to stay here, he doesn't.
我们要怎么解决这个问题
How do we solve that?
好吧  爱瑞丝亲爱的
Okay, Iris, honey.
我之前处过的关系都没有
I haven't always been in the near-perfect relationship
现在这样近乎完美过
that I'm in now.
所以听有经验的人说一句
So take it from someone with experience,
你俩能解决这问题的唯一方法就是齐心协力
the only way you two solve this problem is together.
而你在这里是找不到答案的
And you're not going to find your answers here.
对  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
-你得去追她  -别这样
- You need to go after her. - Oh, come on.
饶了我吧  你见识过她的右勾拳吗
Give me a break. Have you seen her right hook?
拉尔夫  她受伤了  我了解的
Ralph, she's hurt, I know.
但这其中还有原由  我能感觉到
But there's something more. I feel it.
她已经下定决心了
She's determined.
重新编程完成
Reprogramming complete.
时间球导航核心已经被锁定到
The Time Sphere's navigation core is now locked
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦的临时信号上
onto Nora West-Allen's temporal signature.
你还解除了西斯科安装在球里的
And you disabled the tracker that Cisco installed
-追踪装置  -是的
- into the Sphere? - Yes.
但是  尖端科研实验室还有警报装置
However, there are still alarms in S.T.A.R. Labs.
如果你想要不被发觉情况下使用球
If you wish to use the Sphere undetected,
就只能在户外使用
you must activate it off-site.
准备去旅游吗
Planning a trip?
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
跟着你然后从门缝挤进来的
Followed you then stretched under the door.
对了  你们有谁想过
By the way, was anybody ever gonna
告诉我这个密室的吗
tell me about this secret room?
这里还有什么  保龄球道还是什么
What else do we got in here? A bowling alley or something?
拉尔夫  我没有这闲工夫
Ralph, I don't have time for this.
实际上  你看起来时间多的很
Actually, it looks like you have all the time in the world.
你阻止不了我的
You're not gonna stop me.
谁说要阻止你了
Who said anything about stopping you?
我就位了
I'm in position.
斯旺  我说我准备好了
Thawne, I said I'm ready.
等下就知道你准没准备好了
We shall see if you're ready.
现在  跑吧
Now run.
听我说  诺拉
Now listen to me, Nora.
呼吸  呼吸
Breathe. Breathe.
你伸出手  但那里空无一人
You're reaching out and nobody's there.
孤独是痛苦的
The loneliness is pain.
痛苦在你脑中疾驰
Pain racing through your mind.
压倒你  破坏你
Crushing you, wrecking you,
将你的灵魂击碎成上百万的碎片
shattering your soul into a million little pieces.
突然之间  你不再是你
And suddenly, you are no longer you.
你现在是不同物质的一部分
You're part of something different now.
是负力的一部分
Part of a negative force.
没起作用
It didn't work.
斯旺  为什么没起作用
Thawne, why didn't it work?
-你准备好了吗  -准备好到达
- Are you ready? - All set to hit
每小时88英里了
88 miles an hour!
开始吧
Here we go.
打开时间缺口
Open the time breach!
拉尔夫  快点
Ralph, hurry up!
所以制冷雾化器可以将
So the Cryo-Atomizer has the ability
粒子散布到大气层之中
to disperse particles into the atmosphere.
那些粒子会极度降低原子的速度
Particles that slow down atoms to a grinding halt.
-它们速度越慢  -就会越冷
- And the slower they get- - The colder they get.
-究竟能有多冷  -完全零度
- How cold are we talking? - Absolute zero.
如果我们将它和冰柱超能力结合
And if we combine them with Icicle's meta-powers...
他可能会让中城进入一个新的冰河时代
He could plunge Central City into a new Ice Age.
这里有些好消息
There is some good news.
我想我们能追踪雾化器中的
I think we can track the nano-cryoparticles
制冷纳米粒子
inside the atomizer.
我们只需要设定一个制动翻转扫描仪
We just have to reprogram an oscillating inversion scanner.
你能不能跑到楼下的仓库去
Do you mind running to the downstairs storage area
拿来一个
and grabbing it?
等下  你应该用改进后的阵列场
Wait. You should use a modified field array.
楼上储藏室有一个
There's one in the upstairs archives.
不不  其实制动翻转扫描仪
No, no, actually the inversion scanner
是最好的  谢谢
would work best. Thank you.
不不  我们前年升级阵列场之后就不同了
No, no. Not since we upgraded our field arrays last year.
你要是多来几次就知道了
You know you would know that if you visited more,
而不是需要什么才来
not just when you needed something.
显然  只有我需求错的时候
Apparently, only when I need the wrong thing.
-翻转扫描仪  -阵列场
- The inversion scanner. - The field array.
我两个都拿来
I'll get both.
或许需要点时间
Might take my time.
你需要帮助吗
You need help?
不
No.
是我错觉  还是这里变冷了
Is it me or is it getting really cold in here?
快跑
Run!
一石二鸟
Two for one.
谁想来个家庭团圆
So who wants a family reunion?
再见  闪电小队
Adieu, Team Flash.
警告  生命垂危
巴里  巴里  挺住啊
Barry. Barry, come on!
快啊  巴仔
Come on, Barr!
我几乎感觉不到他的脉搏了
I can barely feel his pulse.
他的体温过低  心率正在降低
He has hypothermia. His heart rate's dropping.
我们只剩几秒的时间救他
We only have seconds to save him.
-你要做什么    -这个...
- What are you doing? - Well, this--
这个机器有强大能量源
this machine has a large power source
我需要它来救艾伦先生
I need to access to save Monsieur Allen.
注意
Watch out.
这样也可以  后退
That'll work. Stand back.
好了
All right.
这个电流可以加热他
This current should heat up the copper wiring
战衣里的铜线  我们只需要足够的热量
of his suit's circuitry and we need to heat it up enough
让他的极速治疗可以开始
so that his speed healing kicks in.
-这安全吗  -比死安全
- Is this safe? - Safer than dying.
-来吧  艾伦先生  -巴里
- Come on, Monsieur Allen. - Barry?
-加油  -巴仔
- Come on! - Barr!
冰柱  他抓走了她们
Icicle. He has them.
-不行不行  先生  -别  等下  等等
- No, no, no, no, Monsieur. - No, no, wait. No, wait.
之后的  之后的  首先你要休息
In time. In time. First, you rest.
然后我们一起带她们回家
Then we bring them home together.
我们在哪里
Where are we?
另一个唐豪瑟废弃的站点
In another decommissioned Tannhauser site.
这个地方比其他的更隐蔽些
This site is a little more off-the-grid than usual.
这是我们存放最机密项目的地方
It's where we kept our most classified projects.
真棒  我想我们是冰柱的下一个项目了
Great. I guess we are Icicle's next project.
我们得离开这里
We need to get out of here.
那边有个电路板
Well, there's a circuit panel over here.
我想我可以黑进去打开门
I think we can hack it and open the door.
咱俩都不懂电气工程
Neither one of us knows about electrical engineering.
我们最好的赌注是破坏这些超能力手铐
Our best bet is to break me out of these meta-cuffs
然后让冰霜杀手来处理之后的事
and let Killer Frost do the rest.
别傻了  你没法破坏这些东西的
Don't be foolish. You'll never break those.
不比你想电死自己更蠢
Well, it's no more foolish than you electrocuting yourself,
但你真的想的话  随便你
but if you want to, knock yourself out.
你倒挺希望我被电死  对吧
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
我们是怎样沦落到这个地步的
How did we get here?
我是说  你是我妈妈  我是你女儿
I mean, you're my mother and I'm your daughter.
但我从未感受过母爱
But it has never felt like that.
你一直以来都是这么冷漠  疏远
You've always been cold, distant.
你从来就没想成为我生活中的一部分
You never wanted to be a part of my life.
以前都不想  更别说现在
Not then, and certainly not now.
为什么
Why?
我到底做错了什么  你要这样子对我
I mean, what did I ever do to get treated like this?
-什么  -你当初为什么要离开我
- What? - Why did you leave me?
是你先抛下我的
You left me first.
你为了远离我  跨了大半个国家去念书
You went to school across the country to get away from me.
你宁愿在中城工作
You took a job in Central City
也不愿在我实验室所在的城市里工作  凯特琳
instead of working in the the same zip code as my lab, Caitlin,
你还嫁给一个我从来没见过的男人
you were married to a man I never even met.
我明白你的意思
I got the hint,
但请不要混淆事实
but don't you dare mistake things.
我不是先离开的人
I didn't leave first.
我们在这里干什么  你想把我们怎么样
What are we doing here? What do you want with us?
我要你能成为的人
I want what you could be.
-住手  -只是一个小小的血样
- Stop it! - Just a small blood sample.
回头见  斯诺小分队
See you soon, Snow Pack.
-什么  -斯诺小分队
- What? - Snow Pack.
你爸给我们家起的昵称
That was your father's nickname for our family.
我记得  可这为什么吓到你了
I remember, and why is that scaring you?
他说他想要我们能成为那样的人
He said he wanted what we could be
然后就抽了你的血样
and then he took a sample of your blood.
理论上  他可以利用制冷雾化器
Theoretically, he could use the Cryo-Atomizer
来还原创造冰霜杀手的过程
to recreate the process that created Killer Frost.
假如他用来对付你的话
So if he did that to you...
我也会有冰霜人格
I would gain an ice persona.
加上我的血样
And now with a sample of my blood...
他可以制造一种
He can create a serum
可以永久抑制我们人性面的血清
that will permanently suppress our human sides.
他想要一个冰霜家庭
He wants an ice family
他不惜抹除我们的存在来达成目标
and he's willing to erase us to get it.
-拿着我战服  -我的天啊  拉尔夫
- Hold my suit. - Oh, my God, Ralph.
-你有洗过这件玩意吗  -专心点  好吗
Do you ever wash this thing? - Focus, okay?
你准备好要和"不能说出名字的人"谈话吗
You sure you're ready to talk to "He who shall not be named"?
不管有没有  吉迪恩说
Well, whether I am or not, Gideon said
这些是诺拉的最后已知坐标
that these were Nora's last known coordinates.
你来搞定
You're up.
你好  老兄
Hey, bro.
多么无聊的一天  我没说错吧
Uh, what a day. Am I right?
你介意我跟汉尼拔极速者说几句话吗
You mind if I get a quick word there with Hannibal Speedster?
很快的  大概只需要一秒
It's just going to take, like, a second.
是吗
Is that right?
除非你有签署的换班命令
Well, unless you got a signed Shift Change Order,
除了我谁都不能进去  老弟
nobody goes in there but me, bro.
只有你啊
Only you, huh?
好吧  如果你坚持的话
Okay, if you insist.
糟糕
Oh, shrap.
你得抓紧时间
You need to hurry.
这家伙是个混蛋
This guy's such a dick,
我得想些超级混球的事才能维持住这张脸
I got to think super douchey thoughts just to keep this face on.
混球  混球  混球
Douchey, douchey, douchey.
我明明按照你教我的每一步去做
I did everything exactly like you told me.
为什么我就做不成
How come I can't do this?
听着  没积攒足够的怒气  为征途做准备
Listen, not harboring enough rage to fuel your trip
并不是一件让人感到羞耻的事
is not something to be ashamed of.
你只是太像你的父亲
You're just like your father.
你的闪电  是你最强大的优势
Your light is your greatest strength.
-诺拉  -妈妈
- Nora. - Mom?
离他远一点  拜托
Step away from him, please.
妈妈  不要紧的
Mom, it's okay.
艾尔伯德在帮助我
Eobard is helping me.
他有办法让我回家
He has a way for me to get back home.
诺拉  离他远一点  立刻
Nora, step away from him now.
诺拉  听你妈妈的话
Nora, listen to your mother.
爸爸在哪里
Where's Dad?
只有我来了
It's just me.
或许这是件好事  来吧  我们得快点
It's probably for the best. Come on, we have to hurry.
或许这是件好事  是什么意思
What do you mean it's probably for the best?
诺拉  你爸最不想看到的就是
Nora, the last thing your father needs
你和他在一起
is to see you here with him.
她说得没错
She's right about that.
不
No.
不  她错了  我爸也是
No, she's not, and neither is my dad.
诺拉  你爸爸是错了
Nora, your dad was wrong,
但他依旧在乎你
but he still cares about you.
那为什么你来了而他没来
Why are you here and he isn't?
听着  我能理解你现在的感受
Look, I understand how you feel--
是吗
Do you?
你知道自己想要的东西
Do you know what it's like to want something
胜过生命中的一切是什么感觉吗
more than anything else in your whole life?
了解你的父亲
To know your father?
尽你所能跟随着他的脚步
To do your best to follow in his footsteps?
让他感到骄傲
To make him proud?
他怎么能抛下我
How could he leave me?
-慢着  慢着  够了  -诺拉
- Wait, wait! That's enough! - Nora.
他怎么可以不再爱我了
How could he stop loving me?
不
No!
你总是说一些居高临下的
It's always the same condescending
"我知道的比你多"的废话
"I know better than you" Crap.
你一直都没变过
and you never change!
她想要杀了我
She's trying to kill me.
-还有谁知道  -所有人
- Who else knows? - Everyone.
你是时候回家了
It's time for you to go home.
再见  诺拉
Good-bye, Nora.
再见  诺拉  再见  诺拉
Goodbye, Nora. Goodbye, Nora.
她消失了
She's gone.
她消失了是什么意思  消失去哪里
What the hell do you mean she's gone? Gone where?
我不知道在哪里  我只知道在什么时候
I don't know where. I only know when.
2019年
2019.
诺拉说你告诉她回去的方法...
When Nora said you showed her a way back...
她说的是你那种方法
she meant your way.
是的  我犯了错误
Yes. And I made a mistake.
她想回家  我尽力帮助她
She wanted to go home, I tried to help her.
但听好  爱瑞丝  你必须找到她
But listen, Iris, you have to find her.
她需要她的家人
She needs her family.
她的家人不包括你
And that family does not include you.
但确实包括巴里
But it does include Barry.
她需要你们俩团结一起
She needs you both united.
这话我只说一次
I'm only going to say this once.
你没有资格对我们评议是非
You don't get to comment on us.
你别管我们的闲事
You stay the hell out of our business
否则你活不过那个计时器结束的一刻
or you won't even make it to the end of that timer.
我欣赏你的愤怒
I like your anger,
但别让它赶走巴里
but don't let it drive Barry away.
你唯一能帮助诺拉的方式
The only way for you to help Nora
就是作为家人
is by doing it as a family.
否则你就是在离开巴里
Otherwise, you're simply leaving Barry
就像他离开诺拉一样
the exact same way he left Nora.
爱瑞丝  我们得撤了
Iris, we got to bail.
他们找到混蛋警官了
They found Officer Jackass.
想想吧
Think about it.
爱瑞丝  快
Iris, please.
有其他人在你的脑中是什么感觉
What's it like having another person in your head?
挺疯狂的
Pretty crazy.
她第一次出现时
I mean, when she first showed up,
我很想摆脱她
I couldn't wait to get rid of her,
但她消失时
but when she disappeared,
我更想让她回来
I tried even harder to get her back.
最后是什么让她回来的
What finally brought her back?
家人
Family.
她保护了我们
She protected us.
我很高兴有人能照顾你
Well, I'm glad you had someone there for you.
妈妈  你刚才真是聪明了
Hey, Mom, that was pretty clever what you did.
弄明白了冰柱的计划
Figuring out Icicle's plan.
我记得你也帮了大忙
Well, I recall you helped with that too.
我们不斗嘴作对的时候
It's amazing what we can do
所能做的真是太让人震惊了
when we're not trying to rip each other's heads off.
离她远点
Stay away from her.
我会再回来找她的
I'll come back for her later.
首先  我们先聊下
First, we have some catching up to do.
什么
What?
不
No!
凯特琳
Caitlyn!
无结果
没有线索
There's no leads.
没有冰柱的的搜索结果
There's no hits on Icicle's cryosignature,
也没有面部识别  什么都没有
no reads on facial recognition, nothing.
巴里  我们会找到他的  我们一直如此
Barr, we'll find him. We always do.
怎么找呢  乔  我们怎么找到他们
How, Joe? How are we gonna find them?
凯特琳被绑架了
Caitlyn's kidnapped.
我们需要凯特琳来找到凯特琳
We need Caitlyn to find Caitlyn.
西斯科在另一个地球
Cisco's on another Earth
爱瑞丝不回我的电话  我...
and Iris won't even answer my calls! I...
我不知道怎么搞定这些
I don't know how to fix any of this.
我能试试吗
If I might?
我突然想到
It occurs to me that hiding
在大海中藏针很容易
a needle in a haystack is good.
在针海里藏针
Hiding a needle in a stack of needles?
更容易
That's better.
这是这一区域所有的冷点
These are all the cold spots in the area.
你认为冰柱用寒冷的地方
You think Icicle is masking his cryo-signature
来掩盖他的冷信号吗
with someplace that's already cold?
给了他完美的掩护
Giving him the perfect cover.
所以我们就重新关注我们的研究
So we just refocus our search,
寻找现存冷点的
look for temperature anomalies
温度异常现象  解决
in already existing cold spots, et voila.
太棒了  我去重新分配卫星
This is great. I'll start retasking the satellites.
-谢谢你的帮助  -微薄之力
- Hey, thanks for your help. - The least I can do.
我发现一个冷点峰值
I've got a cold spike.
这可是一大堆针啊
That's quite a stack of needles.
托马斯  你在里面吗
Thomas, are you in there?
托马斯  拜托了
Thomas, please.
现在是时候来见你的另一半了
Now it's time to meet your better half.
完美
Perfection.
你怎么出来的
How did you get out?
我  我只是举起了手
Me? I just raised my hands.
是你冻住了我的手铐
You were the one who froze my cuffs
然后手铐就像玻璃一样碎了
so they shattered like glass.
好聪明  凯特琳
Clever, Caitlyn.
她死后我可能会想念她呢
I'm almost gonna miss her when she's dead.
现在没有回头路了  是时候做选择了
No turning back now. Time to make a choice.
你要不救她
You either save her...
要不和我打
Or fight me.
救她
Save her.
我去抓他
I'm gonna go get him.
好的  再解释为什么是我在这做这些
Okay, explain again why I'm here doing this
而不是别人
and not anybody else?
我们目前有点人手不够
It appears we're a bit short staffed at the moment.
好吧  我们就我们吧
All right, if it's just us, it's just us.
-我们来做吧  -我们来吧
- Let's do this. - Let's do this thing.
-发生什么了  -时机正好
- What's happening? - Oh, great timing.
好时机  你来
Oh, yeah, good timing. Oh, you do this.
好的  冰柱把凯特琳和她妈妈
Okay, Icicle has Caitlyn and her mom
关在巴德兰斯北部的某个洞穴里
in some caves north of the Badlands.
闪电侠已经在现场了
Well, the Flash is already on the scene.
据我们所知  问题已经解决了
So for all we know, the problem is already solved.
-各位  我有个问题  -没有
- Guys, I have a problem. - Or not.
我得让卡拉穿过制冷室
I need to phase Carla out of a cryo-chamber
但太冷了  我没法触碰
but it's too cold. I can't even touch it.
好吧  我们需要加热  要快
All right, we need heat fast.
用他生成闪电怎么样
What if he generates a lightning bolt?
他不能扔闪电  那会杀死她的
He can't throw a bolt. That would kill her.
那他为什么不握住它
Then why doesn't he just, uh, hold onto it?
-那会杀死他的  -不不  他说得对
- That could kill him! - No, no. He's right.
如果你相位移动  闪电就不会伤害你
The lightning cannot hurt you if you are in phase.
如果我一半的分子都在相位移动
If half my molecules are in phase,
电会从一个稳定分子到另一个稳定分子
the electricity would hop from stable molecule to stable molecule.
产生电流桥
Creating an electronic bridge
从而产生你所需的热量  解决
that will generate the heat that you need, et viola.
还不会电死他  他能穿进去
Without electrocuting him, he can phase in,
抓着她  再穿出来
grab her, and then phase out.
所有这些在0.3秒内完成
All in 3/10s of a second.
救出你了
I got you.
我来暖她
I'm going to warm her up, all right?
好浪费
What a waste.
我想让你变得完美
I wanted to make you perfect.
现在我必须灭了你
Now I must end you.
不可能
Impossible.
凯特琳
Caity?
爸爸
Dad?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
是你吗  真的是你吗
Is it you? Is it really you?
是我
It's me.
-真的是我  -天啊
- It's really me. - Oh. Oh, my God.
你会好起来的  你只需慢慢来
You're going to be okay. You just need to take it slow.
托马斯
Thomas?
天啊
My God!
-你有没有...  -我没事
- Are you-- - I'm okay.
我受了伤  但冰霜杀手有冰疗能力
I took a beating but Killer Frost ice healing kicked in.
多亏了爸爸  我没事了
I'm going to be fine thanks to Dad.
这怎么可能
Well, how--how is this possible?
我看到冰柱要杀了凯特琳
Well, I saw Icicle about to kill Caitlyn,
我找到了冲破的力量
and I found the strength to break through.
就像冰霜杀手  爸爸救了我
Just like Killer Frost, Dad saved me.
你也救了我  凯特
Well, you saved me too, Caity.
多亏了你
I mean, thanks to you,
我想我可能终于驱逐了这个怪物
I think I may have finally banished this monster.
很好
That's good.
就留给我一个怪物要杀了
That just leaves one more monster for me to kill.
快跑
Run!
离开这里  我来解决
Get out of here. I'll take care of this.
刀不错  我有两把
Cool knife. I've got two.
凯特琳  快跑
Caitlyn, run!
爸  不要啊
Dad? Dad. Please.
凯特琳
Caitlyn.
爸  我告诉你快走了
Dad, I told you to go.
之前我已经离开过一次
I already left once before.
离开了你们两个
Left both of you.
是我人生中最大的错误
Worst mistake I've ever made in my entire life.
我不会再犯这样的错误了
I wasn't going to make that again.
家人不能抛弃家人
Family shouldn't leave family.
我会一直爱你
I'll always love you.
凯特琳和她妈妈怎么样了
How's Caitlyn and her mom?
凯特琳还在做一些测试
Caitlin's still running some tests,
但她认为卡拉会没事的
but she thinks Carla's gonna be okay.
考虑到现在的处境她还好
I mean, as okay as she can be given the circumstances.
为什么二代蝉今晚在那里
Why was Cicada II even there tonight?
为什么攻击冰柱和凯特琳
I mean, why attack Icicle and Caitlin?
也许冰霜超能力者并不是首要目标
Perhaps the ice meta were not the primary target.
二代蝉要制冷雾化器做什么
What could Cicada II want with the Cryo-Atomizer?
今晚我们无法弄清楚了
Well, we're not gonna figure it out tonight.
所以今晚我们休息吧
So let's rest tonight.
你回家里来吗
Are you coming back to the house?
不  我今晚呆在阁楼
No, I'm gonna stay at the loft tonight.
真的吗
You are?
是的
Yeah.
我们应该谈谈
We should talk.
有点尴尬
Awkward a bit.
你去了未来
So you went to the future?
约翰·斯塔莫斯依然很帅
Yeah. John Stamos still handsome.
他从不变老
He'll never not age.
从不  他很帅
No, never. Man, he looks good.
这个温血石蕊检测
So this endothermic litmus test
会产生化学计量反应
would've created a stoichiometric reaction.
如果你的系统中有残留的超能力DNA  它...
If there was any residual meta DNA in your system, it--
会变成白色  我知道
Would've turned white. I know.
它依然是绿色  所以你没问题
And it's still green, so you're clean.
你不是超能力者
You're not a meta.
这些是我以前要找到爸爸的线索
Those were all the clues that I used to find dad.
包括一些我从你文件室
Including some files that I may have stolen
偷的文件
from your file room.
凯特琳的元素
凯特琳和托马斯的邪恶元素周期表
Caitlin and Thomas' infamous Periodic Table.
钅那
Nerdonium.
他从我这里偷的
You know, he stole that one from me.
真的吗  我以为是他
Really? I thought he came up with that
在修厨房水槽的时候想到的
while he was fixing the kitchen sink.
是我想到的
No, I thought of that.
细想一下  也是我修的厨房水槽
Come to think of it, I also fixed the kitchen sink.
我最好回去了
Well, I--I better be going.
晚安  凯特
Good night, Caity.
妈
Mom? Um...
你想去喝一杯吗
Do you want to maybe go get a drink?
你可以给我讲讲你发明的元素
You can tell me more about elements you invented.
现在或者改天
Now or whenever.
其实现在就是时候
No, actually, now would be perfect.
路口有一个小酒吧
There's a little wine bar around the corner.
回家吗
Heading home?
像巴里说的  还有乔...
Well, it's like Barry said--and Joe--
-我做得够多了  -他们是这么说的
- I've done enough. - They did say that.
但你还是留在了这里
But you hung around anyway.
是的
Oui , I did.
当巴里需要你的时候你在这里
You were there for Barry when he needed you.
没错
Oui , I was.
你帮助救了凯特琳的妈妈
And you helped saved Caitlyn's mom.
是的  我做了这些
Yes, that's right. I did all those things.
我不应该做这些吗
I should not have done those things?
我只是说也许你还有更多要做的
I'm just saying maybe you have more to do...
为了你的家庭
For your family.
我只想让我的家人重归于好
I just wanted my family back together.
即使这意味着做些夸张的事情比如时空穿越
Even if that meant doing something drastic like time travel.
我明白
Yeah, I get that.
比别人都懂
More than anyone.
你对斯旺的看法是对的
You were right about Thawne.
我认为他在操控诺拉
I think he's manipulating Nora,
但我依然相信他
but I also believe him.
诺拉回到了我们的时空
Nora is back here in our time.
我...
I was...
错了
Wrong.
我不应该离开诺拉的
I shouldn't have left Nora
也不应该不和你商量做决定
or made that decision without you.
不论我们要想明白什么
Whatever it is that we have to figure out,
我们应该一起做
we should've done it together.
家人不会抛弃家人
Family doesn't leave family.
你不是唯一犯这个错误的人
Well, I mean you weren't the only one to make that mistake.
我不应该背着你穿越到未来
I shouldn't have gone to the future without you.
我不应该那样离开你
I shouldn't have left you like that.
这也是我那么生你的气的原因
I mean, that was the same thing that I got so mad at you for.
现在我知道了如果我们不互相支持
But I know now that we can't solve this
我们就无法解决
if we don't stick together.
我和你一起都差点解决不了问题
I can barely solve things with you,
没了你
so without you...
我们已经开起玩笑了吗  真的吗
Are we making jokes already? Really?
我们接孩子回家吧
Let's bring our kid home.
我还想告诉你些事情
There's something else that I wanted to tell you.
巴里  斯旺谈论起诺拉的样子
Barry, the way that Thawne looks when he talks about Nora.
我只在另一个人的身上见过
I've only ever seen that in one other person.
你
You.
你的意思是
What are you saying?
我觉得斯旺也许是真心关心诺拉
I think Thawne might actually care about Nora.
中城新闻图报
麦克劳街
莫伊街
快了  格蕾丝
Soon, Grace.
快了
Soon.